Guide to the Truman A. Warner Papers MS 026
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series I, Research Files
  - Music
    - Solstice, 1978-1987 (Box 21, Folder 53)
      Articles on group that performed from 1978 to 1987 composed of Richard Brooks, Guy Dedell, and Andy LaFreniere.
    - Travers, Mary, 1970-1994 (Box 21, Folder 54)
      Articles describing activities of Redding resident, Mary Travers, of Peter, Paul, and Mary.
    - Western Connecticut Symphony Orchestra, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 55)
      Two articles on short-lived orchestra. Skitch Henderson directed orchestra of 1981
  - Native American Indians
    See also Student Research Papers #44: The Indians of South Western Connecticut by Craig H. Tomkinson. 1966.
    Thesis: Scaticook Indians of Kent, Connecticut by John F. Wilbur.
    History, establishment to the decline (1745 to 1965), including the basket industry.
    See also: E99.S25 W5 1966 located in WCSU Archives
    Gambling on Indians reservations - Connecticut; Casinos -- Government policy -- Connecticut -- Ledyard; Casinos -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Pequot Indians - History; Scaticook Indians - Social life and customs; Schaghticoke Indians - Connecticut - Kent; Casinos -- Government policy; Pequot Indians - Gambling; Paugusset Indians; Mashuntucket Pequots; Ledyard (Conn.) -- Social conditions; Ledyard (Conn.) -- Economic conditions; Indians of North American -- Connecticut -- History; Paleo Indians - Connecticut -History
    - Bridgeport Casino, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 56-58)
      Focus on history, support and eventual death in Senate of Bridgeport Casino Bill on November 18, 1995. Gov. John Rowland, Mirage Resorts, Joseph Gamin, Pequots, U. S. Senator Daniel Inouye (D) Hawaii.
    - Indians, 1959-1996 (Box 21, Folder 59-61)
      Articles illustrate the growing concern about the loss of Paleo-Indian Burial Sites, artifacts and relics due to the growth of construction, e.g., I-84 and Route 7, growing Indian sensitivity to excavation of burial sites, Indian Affairs Council, litigation and injunctions by Five Tribes under the Federal Non-Intercourse Act 1972, casinos, Native American Advisory Council, and Golden Hill Tribe membership. Local interest: Quarry Center, Danbury Airport.
    - Indians, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 62-64)
      Folders 5, 6, and 7 focus on the history of aboriginal Indian population in Southwestern Connecticut and Long Island Sound. Bulletin of the Archaeological Society of Connecticut, April 1936, published by the Peabody Museum. Student research paper: Historic and Prehistoric Indian of the Connecticut Valley by Agnes Lehning. nd.
    - Indians, nd, undated (Box 21, Folder 65-68)
      Pamphlets from the Institute for American Studies, formerly AIAI, on culture/anthropological research. Also, notes and chapters from books on anthropology, history, and culture.
    - Indians, 1967-1988 (Box 21, Folder 69-71)
      Excerpts from books on anthropology, history, culture, ethnography, division of labor, and migration to Americas.
    - Indians, 1705-1988 (Box 21, Folder 72-77)
      Research notes and writings, bibliographies, clippings on Uncas, Pequots, and Navahos. Bulletins/pamphlets on Native American culture, fish fertilizer, natural herb products, legends, land use, patterns and subsistence agriculture/techniques. Indian Heritage day at Rogers Park, Scott Fanton Museum Indian exhibit, Society for the Preservation of Indian Culture.
    - Indians (Danbury) Fanton Notes, 1837-1987 (Box 21, Folder 78)
      Research notes from Nichols Diary at Scott Fanton Museum. Research Paper: Joe's Hill and the Road to Danbury by Lydia V. Potter. 1935. Other topics include Indian artifacts at Lake Candlewood, Joyceland, and Squantz Pond.
    - Indians - New England and Connecticut, 1895-1993 (Box 21, Folder 79-81)
      Includes research notes, clippings, AIAI bulletins, bulletins from seminars, newsletters from ASCH, and maps. Booklet: Rooted Like The Ash Trees, New England Indians and the Land by Richard G. Carlson. 1987.
    - Indians - New England and Connecticut, 1980-1996 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
      Articles on land issues, political campaign contributions, Foxwoods, Mohegan Sun, Uncasville, Indian gaming and land issues, and recipes from E. Barrie Kavatsch.
    - Eagle Wing Press, Autumn 1984, undated (Box OS 1, Folder *)
    - Indian Gambling Casinos, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Clippings on local/national issues. See also: Pequots, Paugussetts, and Mohegans.
    - Mashuntucket Pequots, 1978-1997 (Box 22, Folder 4-11)
      Folders 16, and 17 focus on history of the Pequots land claims in Ledyard, tribal recognition (under President Reagan) to restitution of ancestral lands and sovereign nation status. Ratification of gaming compacts and slot machine operations by Gov. Lowell P. Weicker in 1993. Eastern Pequot Tribes claims in North Stonington Tribal courts, Office of Tribal Justice, Janet Reno on criminal jurisdiction for reservations, Indians Bureau Probe, Indian Child Welfare Act, blood requirements for bona fide recognition to Pequot tribe, and Foxwoods Casino expansion.
    - Mohegan, 1950-1996 (Box 22, Folder 12-14)
      Research notes and clippings. Articles cover Nathan Gold, John Underwood, David Newham, Chief Tantaquidgeon, Fort Shantock State Park and the Mohegan Congregational Church 1831. The American Graves Protection and Repatriation Action 1990 provided recovery of burial and sacred artifacts. Federal recognition and 240 acre reservation granted in 1994 by Bureau of Indian Affairs. History of Birch Hill Game Park by H. E. Hillery, Putnam County Historian; and, The Mohegans of Stockridge by Patrick Frazer (research notes, table of contents and bibliography only).
    - Paugusset Indians, 1973-1993 (Box 22, Folder 15-20)
      Articles on reclamation of reservations under Indian Trade and Intercourse Act 1790, history of Golden Hill Reservation in Trumbull, renewed land claims in Monroe, Shelton, Kent, Bridgeport, liens on Southbury, retaliatory litigation, Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA), burden of proof for tribal recognition, Indian Gaming Regulation Action 1988, in depth refutation of Paugusset claims by James P. Lynch, ethno historian and anthropologist.
    - Scaticook Indians, 1492-1992, undated (Box 22, Folder 21-22)
      Research notes, correspondence, chapters from books, flyers, and bulletins. Tribe renamed Schaghticoke. Black and white photograph (2½ x 3 ½) of Princess Eunice Mauee grave. Booklet: The Schaghticokes. Decendants From Our First Americans.
    - Schaghticoke Indians-Kent, 1942-1996 (Box 22, Folder 23-24)
      Articles describe history, destruction of burial grounds, need for Indians Affairs Commission, American Indian culture, tribal recognition requirements, litigation, court settlements, leadership problems, casinos, burial sites.
    - Shepaug Valley A.I.A.I., 1973-1994 (Box 22, Folder 25-26)
      Articles cover history of Shepaug Valley Historical Society and the AIAI. Late in the 1960s there became a need to preserve Paleo Indian sites and Indian artifacts in the Housatonic and Shepaug Valleys. Titus Field Project and other archaeological digs were set up to preserve/rescue the heritage of prehistoric Indian culture from growing development and construction. 1974 saw the groundbreaking for AIAI Museum, which is now an active educational research facility supervising digs in the Still River and Housatonic Valleys.
    - Wojciechowski, Franz L. - The Paugusset Tribes, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 27)
      The Ethnohistory of the Paugusset Tribes: An Exercise in Research Methodology review by Dr. Laurie Weinstein. Copy transcript: The Paugusset Tribes: An Ethnohistorical Study of the Tribal Interrelationship of the Indians in the Lower Housatonic River Area published by the Catholic Unit of Nijmegen Department of Cultural and Social Anthropology.
  - Parks, Recreation, Open Spaces
    Lake Lillinonah; Lake Mamanasco (Ridgefield); Lake Zoar (Newtown); Open Spaces - Connecticut - Ridgefield; Open Spaces - Connecticut - Sherman; Lake Mauweehoo (Sherman); Open Spaces - Connecticut - Redding; Hatters Park (Danbury, Conn.); Appalachian Trail - Connecticut; Bear Mountain Park (Danbury, Conn.); Kennedy Park (Danbury, Conn; Kenosia Park (Danbury, Conn); Hiking -- Connecticut; Huntington State Park, Connecticut; Rogers Park, Danbury, Conn; Richter Park, Danbury, Conn; Recreational Areas-Lakes-Connecticut-Danbury Region; Recreational Areas-Connecticut-Danbury; Waters Edge Project (New Fairfield, Conn.); Tarrywile Park, Danbury, Conn; Route 7 Linear Park - Connecticut; Candlewood, Lake (Conn.); Open Spaces - Connecticut - Danbury; Open Spaces - Connecticut - Housatonic Valley Region (Conn.); Open Spaces - Connecticut - Bethel; Open Spaces - Connecticut - Brookfield; Lake Waubeeka (Danbury).; Kenosia, Lake (Conn.); Lake Putnam (Redding); Land use -- Connecticut -- Danbury; Lake Waramaug (Washington); Open Spaces - Connecticut - New Milford; Open Spaces - Connecticut - Newtown; Open Spaces - Connecticut - Kent; Open Spaces - Connecticut - New Fairfield
    - Appalachian Trail - Connecticut, 1979-1983 (Box 22, Folder 28)
      Attempts to re-route Appalachian Trail in Connecticut.
    - Bear Mountain Park (Danbury, Conn.), 1971-1983 (Box 22, Folder 29)
      Bear Mountain Reservation and its transformation into a Park.
    - Candlewood Lake (Conn.) - Recreation, 1967-1996 (Box 22, Folder 30-32)
      Aspects of the Lake: Boating, docks, pollution, weeds, housing. Four issues of Candlewood Comment, A Monthly Digest of Lake News. (June, August, September, 1937; September 1940), and Construction of Bathhouse, Danbury Park, Lake Candlewood, City of Danbury, Connecticut, City Project No. 67-5, 1967. September, 1937; September 1940), and Construction of Bathhouse, Danbury Park, Lake Candlewood, City of Danbury, Connecticut, City Project No. 67-5, 1967.
    - Hatters Park (Danbury, Conn.), 1980-1981 (Box 22, Folder 33)
      The purchase of land south of Candlewood Lake to develop Hatters Park.
    - Hiking - Connecticut, 1979-1995 (Box 22, Folder 34)
      Maps and descriptions of hiking trails in the Danbury region, and Walking with the Trees; 12 Hikes in and around Fairfield County by David Rothenberg. 1978.
    - Huntington State Park - Connecticut, 1950-1977 (Box 22, Folder 35)
      The gift of Archer and Anna Hyatt Huntington and its development.
    - Kennedy Park (Danbury, Conn.), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 36)
      Development of the small triangular park in downtown Danbury in 1966.
    - Kenosia Park (Danbury, Conn.), 1963-1978 (Box 22, Folder 37)
      Parkland use for school becomes political issue.
    - Land Use (Danbury, Conn.), 1950-1973 (Box 22, Folder 38)
      Urban spread. Maps by Technical Planning Associates of New Haven describing Danbury Land Use in 1950s; and, The Environmental Review Team Evaluation of Land Use Proposals by the Cooperative Extension Services, The University of Connecticut, 1973.
    - Open Spaces - Bethel, Conn., 1977-1995 (Box 22, Folder 39)
      Bethel Land Trust and Terra Haute land purchase.
    - Open Spaces - Brookfield, Conn., 1963-1993 (Box 22, Folder 40)
      Brookfield Conservation Commission open space purchases. Open Space Progress Report by the Brookfield Conservation Commission, Spring 1975.
    - Open Spaces - Danbury, Conn., 1959-1984 (Box 22, Folder 41)
      Open space and federal monies; Swampfield Land Trust, Old Quarry Nature Center.
    - Open Spaces - Housatonic Valley Region (Conn.), 1977-1986 (Box 22, Folder 42)
      Articles about value of land trusts in Litchfield County - Audubon Society, White Conservancy. Booklet: Open Space and Recreation Plan, Housatonic Valley Region, Connecticut, 1975. Map: Housatonic Valley Region, Reserved Lands, 1979.
    - Open Spaces - Kent, Conn., 1976-1985 (Box 22, Folder 43)
      Stanley Works land grant; Appalachian Trail through Kent and changes.
    - Open Spaces - New Fairfield, Conn., 1967-1979 (Box 22, Folder 44)
      Vaughn's Neck; Squantz Pond State Park; Hidden Valley Nature Center.
    - Open Spaces - New Milford, Conn., 1965-1995 (Box 22, Folder 45)
      Zalesky Wildlife Management Area; Candlewood Lake recreation areas, Weantinoge Heritage lands, and Sunny Valley Preserve.
    - Open Spaces - Newtown, Conn., 1974-1996 (Box 22, Folder 46)
      Ram's Pasture; Catherine McCarthy donation to Nature Conservancy.
    - Open Spaces - Redding, Conn., 1969-1995 (Box 22, Folder 47-48)
      Steichen Memorial Wildlife Preserve; legal tussle of open spaces vs. housing policies; Redding Land Trust; Great Ledge; death of Samuel Ervin Hill, Redding open space advocate. Student paper: The Conservation Commission: It's open space advocate. Student paper: The Conservation Commission: It's Micro and Macro Role in Modern Society" by Susanna Shanahan. 1979.
    - Open Spaces - Ridgefield, 1963-1995 (Box 22, Folder 49)
      Conservation Commission activities.
    - Open Space - Sherman, Conn., 1975-1994 (Box 22, Folder 50)
      Wesleyan University land in Sherman; Boy Scout camp sale; Appalachian Trail reroute; Naromi Land Trust; Carlson Farm.
    - Recreational Areas - Danbury, Conn., 1950-1995 (Box 22, Folder 51)
      Development of parklands and politics of recreation throughout the 45 years.
    - Recreational Areas (Lakes) - Danbury Region, 1984-1996 (Box 22, Folder 52)
      Lake Zoar (Newtown); Lake Kenosia (Danbury); Lake Mauweehoo (Sherman); Lake Putnam (Redding); Lake Mamanasco (Ridgefield); Lake Waramaug (Washington); Lake Lillinonah; Lake Waubeeka (Danbury). (Washington); Lake Lillinonah; Lake Waubeeka (Danbury). Booklet: Control of Water Weeds and Algae by the Connecticut Dept. of Environmental Protection, 1987.
    - Richter Park (Danbury, Conn.), 1967-1995 (Box 22, Folder 53-54)
      Donation of 80 acres by Irene Myers Richter in 1968; arguments for golf course; Richter Memorial Park Authority; referendum on use of land for golf course; development of golf course; and other aspects of Park. General Documents and Specifications of Richter Park Memorial Golf Course by Edward C. Ryder, development of golf course; and other aspects of Park. General Documents and Specifications of Richter Park Memorial Golf Course by Edward C. Ryder, 1968
    - Rogers Park (Danbury, Conn.), 1965-1983 (Box 22, Folder 55)
      Further development of Danbury's first major park; rose garden.
    - Route 7 Linear Park - Connecticut, 1967-1995 (Box 22, Folder 56)
      Plans for a linear park along Route 7 from New Milford to Norwalk; leadership of Arthur Harris of Brookfield.
    - Tarrywile Park (Danbury, Conn.), 1970-1995 (Box 22, Folder 57-60)
      Extensive coverage of purchase of C. D. Parks property by Danbury for 500 acre nature park; rejection of plan by voters in 1973; approval by voters in 1985; development of Tarrywile Park. Student paper: Charles Darling Parks and His Property by Beverly Poodiack, nd. development of Tarrywile Park. Student paper: Charles Darling Parks and His Property by Beverly Poodiack, nd.
    - Waters Edge Project (New Fairfield, Conn.), 1973-1981 (Box 22, Folder 61-62)
      Coverage of concerns of city in development of 253 acre-tract owned by Stephen Weil; legal issues.
  - Police Courts, Fire, Military
    United States Federal Correctional Institute (Danbury, Conn.); Civil Defense -- Connecticut; Police - Special weapons and tactics units; Prisons - United States; Sunday legislation - Connecticut; Correctional institutions -- Connecticut- - Danbury; Danbury (Conn.) -- National Guard; Military museums - Connecticut -Danbury; Police - Connecticut - Danbury; Crime -- Connecticut -- Danbury; Danbury (Conn.) -- Fire Department; Law -- Connecticut; Law enforcement -- Connecticut -- Danbury
    - Civil Defense/Emergencies, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Planning room at City Hall, Peter Winter, Director of C.D.
    - Court House, 1879-1990 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Pictures and copies of articles concerning construction and opening of new Court House on White Street, Juvenile Court moves to old Court House.
    - Crime, 1994-1995 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Articles, newspaper photos, and editorials. Fear in Laurel Gardens, murder of Christopher Hollins, Clinton money for crime war to Danbury, Geoff Ferguson and Redding murders, identification of Romula Sare remains in Bethel.
    - Danbury National Guard/Reserve, 1958-1996 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Research notes, editorials, undated pictures and columns. Reorganization of the 963rd (Commander Albert Tarrant), phasing out of unit, recruiting after Vietnam, local people in military, Marine Corps League, nation's oldest artillery, call to Bosnia. See also: Student Research Papers #57: The Development of the 963rd Field Artillery Battalion from the Colonial Militia to the Nuclear Age Connecticut National Guard by Michael J. Keenan. 1966.
    - Danbury Jail, et al, 1785-1986 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
      Articles, editorials, research notes, and letters to the editor. Pictures of old jail, research notes for talk on program for rededication, property for old jail, closing and renovation of old jail, old jail becomes senior center, and Newgate Prison
    - F.C.I. - Danbury (Federal Correctional Institute), 1968-1997 (Box 23, Folder 7-9)
      Paper: Educational Enculturation of Prison Inmates. F.C.I. model prison, Berrigan Brothers, Rev. Moon enters F.C.I., Orson Wells' War of the Worlds, wardens, Dennis Luther, Robert Gunnel, women prisoners, literacy volunteers among prisoners, and pay scale for employees
    - Fire Department, 1791-1995 (Box 23, Folder 10-14)
      Research notes and newspaper clippings on history back to 1874, and copy of Rules of Order of the Fire Department Committee and Rules and Regulations for the Government of the Danbury Fire Department adopted, November, 1889. James M. Bailey notes, need for new quarters and more men, new fire house on Ives Street, fire in Hull Block, and articles on individual members of the fire departments
    - Fire Department - Old Photos, 1967-1987 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      Newspaper photos of old vehicles, parades, Humane Hose Company, Marshall Sanford, Bethel Department history, and the Ives Street Fire House.
    - Fire Dept. Volunteer History, 1832-1994 (Box 23, Folder 16-17)
      Articles, letters to editor, newspaper photos on various local volunteer fire departments: Germantown, Mill Plain, Independent Hose, Beckerle Company, Beaver Brook, Citizens Hose, Independent Hose #4, Padanaram Water Witch Hose Company, Brookfield, Dodgingtown, Redding, Bethel Fire Fighter Museum. Booklet: Bethel Volunteer Fire Department, Company, Beaver Brook, Citizens Hose, Independent Hose #4, Padanaram Water Witch Hose Company, Brookfield, Dodgingtown, Redding, Bethel Fire Fighter Museum. Booklet: Bethel Volunteer Fire Department, 1831-1978.
    - Fires - Danbury, 1968-1995 (Box 23, Folder 18-20)
      Articles cover fires, arson/homicide, and death of fire fighters in Danbury. See also: Manuscript Collection, Pinkerton Detective Agency..
    - Military, 1932-1994 (Box 23, Folder 21-22)
      Student research paper: The War Memorial by Warren L. Conner. Articles and editorials about the Spanish American and Civil War vets, new VFW home, employment benefits for vets, GI insurance, disabled war vets, women at West Point, General James A. Ryan, D.H.S. ROTC, women and the draft, memories, American Legion, Gus Hennessey, VA Center, Lee Hartell, and Congressional Medal of Honor.
    - Military Museum, 1988-1996 (Box 23, Folder 23)
      Articles, pictures, letters to editor concerning arrival of Yugoslav tank, Danbury and Ridgefield Museums
    - Newtown Jail, 1987-1996 (Box 23, Folder 24)
      Clippings, editorials, and flyer. Newtown fights (and loses) against prison at Fairfield Hills.
    - Pardue Brothers, 1970-1996 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      Bombing of police station and Union Savings Bank, and murder of Frank Gallagher.
    - Police Department, 1950-1978 (Box 23, Folder 26-30)
      Articles, editorials, and photos on Blue Laws - pros and cons, Danbury city/town problem, need for State police, State police and Ridgefield, new State police barracks, opening of new city police station, police headquarters from City Hall to Main Street School, claims of police brutality, lock-up surveillance, union grievances against police, conflict between city and police union, union fight for drug unit, contract dispute, private detectives, and arson in Danbury.
    - Police, 1980-1997 (Box 23, Folder 31-32)
      Newspaper articles on domestic and sensitivity training, Brookfield Police Dept., criticism of Danbury Force, special officers, SWAT Team, Police Union, Street Crime Unit, New Fairfield Police, constables, foot and bicycle patrols, residency requirement, new police, underwater team, police and minorities, and racial problems.
  - Postcard Collection
    The Postcard Collection is organized by state. As might be expected, many postcards depict travel related images, including historic landmarks, scenic wonders, amusements, hotels, and inns. A small portion of the collection is devoted to silent screen actors, birthdays, Valentines Day, and Christmas, as well as leather postcards. The following is a list of states, as well as foreign countries, that are represented in the collection: Alabama, Arizona, Bermuda, California, Canada, Connecticut, D.C., Washington, Europe, Florida, Georgia, Guatemala, Haiti, Illinois, Kansas, Kentucky, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Mexico, Michigan, Missouri, Montana, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Panama Canal, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, South Dakota, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, Vermont, Virginia, West Virginia, Washington, Wisconsin, Wyoming.
    - Postcards, undated (Box 44, Folder *)
  - Railways
    New York Central Railroad Company; New Haven Railroad; Putnam Railroad; Poughkeepsie Bridge; New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Company; Transportation - Connecticut - 19th century; Railroads - Connecticut - History - 19th century; Railroads - Crossings - Connecticut - Safety measures; Shepaug Railroad; Railroads - Planning; ConRail; Railroads - Connecticut - Norwalk - Crossings; Railroads - Connecticut
    - Railways, 1881-1996 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      Clippings from the News-Times outlining growth of the railroad, attempts to extend the line to New Milford, new stations, safety inspections of railroad crossings, review of 100th year anniversary of the Danbury-Norwalk line which opened in 1852, and the Danbury Railroad Museum's 1948 locomotive. crossings, review of 100th year anniversary of the Danbury-Norwalk line which opened in 1852, and the Danbury Railroad Museum's 1948 locomotive.
    - Railroads-Early, 1827-1995 (Box 23, Folder 34)
      Research notes concerning early railroad ideas from the 19th century, newspaper articles on railroad workers' strike, financial troubles of Conrail, and demolition of a wooden trestle bridge in Brookfield.
    - Railroads-Planned, Proposed or Aborted, 1840-1962 (Box 23, Folder 35)
      Research notes concerning various proposals for adding destinations in Connecticut and New York State to the existing lines. Also a map of the route of NY and Boston line as it existed in 1899. NY and Boston line as it existed in 1899.
    - Danbury Railway Museum, 1971-1996 (Box 23, Folder 36)
      Clippings from the News-Times reveal preparations and photographs of the old station and its transformation into the new Railway Museum that opened on April 20, 1996. Two copies of booklet: Danbury Railway Museum,Union Station Dedication, October 29, 1995
    - Railroad Lines and Routes in Danbury Area today under different names. Clippings compare railroad line at Hawleyville between 1881 and 1970. between 1881 and 1970., 1970-1992 (Box 23, Folder 37)